# Oscar Jimenez

https://www.linkedin.com/in/oscarjimenezm

# Summary

SAFe® Product Owner/Product Manager, Scrum Master Certified SMC™, Automation and Machine Learning, RPA DevOps Engineer, analytical Senior Software Developer, strong in design and integration problem-solving ski lls.Expert in Java, C#, Python, Data Analytics with Power BI, Kibana and Grafana, Snowflake, SQL-Oracle databa sesanalysis and design.

# **Experience**

# Staff Engineer, Artificial Intelligence | Machine Learning

Western Union LAROC

2023 - Present (1 year)

As a Machine Learning Engineer and part of the Data Science Industrialization team charged with building and automating high-quality data science pipelines that power key business applications with advanced analytics/AI/ML. Define and maintains ML Ops best practices and deploy and maintain production analytics and data science modeling workflows.

The responsibilities of This role include, converting data/ML pipelines into scalable pipelines based on the infrastructure available, enabling production models across the ML lifecycle, performance metrics, and model monitoring dashboards, CI/CD orchestration for data science pipelines, managing the production deployments and post-deployment model lifecycle management activities: drift monitoring, model retraining, and model technical evaluation & business validation and work with stakeholders to assist with ML pipeline -related technical issues and support modeling infrastructure needs to monitor robots' performance and mitigate possible affectations. Develop and maintain data analytics, alerts for processes, and keep track of the whole operation. Analyze technical requirements and design workflow based on specifications, in collaboration with business analysts. Collaborate and support the automation teams and provide solutions on development tools and useful appliances. Provide coach and training support on the automation teams.

Technologies: AWS, Cloudbees, Splunk, Dynatrace, Snowflake, Java, Python, H20, Gitlab, CI/CD.

# **Chair of the Technology Academy**

CIT-ULACIT

2022 - 2023 (1 year)

The chair of the Technology Academy is responsible for the planning, organization, and control of all activities related to the Technology Academy at the Center for Technological Innovation CIT. Supervise and hires teachers, ensuring all aspects that affect the academic quality and efficiency of the training programs, responsible for ensuring the efficiency of the services associated with the teaching function, such as induction and teacher training.

Advising for academic improvement, administration and training of academic staff, development of new projects in the teaching area, supervising the development of the academy's curriculum, presiding over the hiring tribunals, supervising the content of syllabi, and approving the uploading of documents in the Blackboard and/or Canvas system, supervising the process of supervision of attendance and teacher compliance (absences, incapacities, tardiness, etc.).

Approve and sign teachers' lists for issuance of contracts, review and sign teaching contracts for teaching periods, analyze and approve syllabi of those courses to be taught in tutorial format and manage the process of evaluation and supervision of content taught for the payment of tutorials, approve extraordinary withdrawals of subjects and courses for sufficiency, execute the annual evaluation of teaching performance.

## **Robotics and Intelligent Automation LAROC Manager**

Western Union LAROC

2020 - 2023 (3 years)

Automation Control Management - Latin American Regional Operation Center | Robotics and Intelligent Automation, as Manager to the RPA Controller Team, supporting the global automation RPA operations, as an Infrastructure administrator performing tasks as, Install and evaluating software and applications to be used in-house, as part of various automation processes, in order to minimize day to day operation effort. Data analytics through MS Power BI, to monitor robots' performance and mitigate possible affectations. Develop and maintain, data analytics, and alerts for processes, and keep track of the whole operation. Analyze technical requirements and design workflow based on specifications, in collaboration with business analysts. Collaborate and support the automation teams and provide solutions on development tools and useful appliances. Provide coach and training support on the automation teams.

Infrastructure analytical, research for new technologies, coaching and training the teams on weekly meetings about, issues, new tools or procedures, Scrum implementation coach, and development of new tools for use in RPA solutions.

Technologies: Blue Prism, Uipath, AbbyyFlexicapture, Jira, VMware vSphere, Scrum, Al, Citrix, CyberArch, Jenkins, CI/CD, Python, Power BI, snowflake.

#### **RPA Automation DevOps Engineer**

Kuehne + Nagel

2019 - 2020 (1 year)

In this position, I performed as Automation DevOps Engineer, supporting the global automation RPA development teams from SSC Costa Rica, SSC Belgrade, United States, Canada and SSC Greece and SSC Philippines, as a Infrastructure administrator performing task as, Install and evaluate software and applications to be used in-house, as part of various automation processes, in order to minimize day to day operation effort. Data analytics through Kibana and grafana, to monitor robots' performance and mitigate possible affectations Develop and maintain automation processes, as a service, and keep track of the whole operation. Analyze technical requirements and design workflow based on specifications, in collaboration with business analysts. Collaborate and support the automation teams and provide solutions on development tools and useful appliances. Provide training and support on the various automations developed. provide and maintenance of new virtual machines, infrastructure analytical, create and management about systems alerts using Kibana and Grafana, research for new technologies, coach and training the teams on weekly meetings, new tools or procedures, Scrum implementation coach and development of new tools for use in RPA solutions.

Technologies: UIPath Studio, UIPath Orchestrator, AbbyFlexicapture, Automation Anywhere, ElasticSearch, Java, Php,Python, Grafana, Kibana, BitBucket, Jira, VMware vSphere, Centreon, Scrum, Al, Data Science.

## **Executive Professional Technological Development**

Universidad Nacional de Costa Rica (State Public University)

2014 - 2019 (5 years)

This project is a customized framework platform that uses the Universidad Nacional for handling a large number of critical administrative areas such as HR and finance.

In this position, I performed as a Product Owner / Scrum Master role, involving a framework created by the Universidad Nacional, which requires research and development, and is programmed in Java using frameworks like Spring, Hibernate, JSF, JPA, and Oracle as database provider.

Testing using Selenium, JUnit and data migration and performance test using JMeter and UiPath.

Technologies: JSF, Spring, Spring security, Spring batch, Maven, Hibernate, Spring JPA, Java, Oracle and Jasper Reports, Apache Velocity, Jira and Confluence from Atlassian, JMeter, Uipath.

## **Education**

## Instituto Tecnólogico de Costa Rica

Data Science Program 2022 - Present

## **Universidad Metropolitana Castro Carazo**

Education 2018 - Present

## **Universidad Fidelitas**

Information Systems Engineering 2017 - Present

#### **Universidad Panamericana**

Systems Engineering 2013 - Present

## **Berkeley College**

Associate, Information Technology Management 2002 - Present

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

RPA Certified Developer, BluePrism - BluePrism

**SAFe® Product Owner/Product Manager Training** 

RPA Certified Developer, UIPath - UIPath

**UIPath Orchestrator Training, UIPath** - UIPath

# UlPath Security Training, UlPath - UlPath

# RPA Developer - SAP Automation, UIPath - UIPath

# **Skills**

AWS Amazon Web Services • Snowflake • Cloudbees • Spinnaker • Dynatrace • GitLab • Cl/CD • Scrum Master • Microsoft Power BI • Tableau